<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BNU-Statistics with R</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on BNU-Statistics with R</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: Model Fitting with Linear Regression</title>
      <link>/2020/09/30/week-2-regression-and-fitting-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/30/week-2-regression-and-fitting-models/</guid>
      <description>This week we will cover data summaries, data structure, linear regression and its assumptions.
At the beginning of each session we will need to load our libraries, so let’s load the packages for this week
library(tidyverse)library(plotrix)library(ggpubr) #install.packages(&amp;quot;ggpubr&amp;quot;)library(qqplotr) #install.packages(&amp;quot;qqplotr&amp;quot;)library(PerformanceAnalytics)#install.packages(&amp;quot;PerformanceAnalytics&amp;quot;)library(gcookbook)library(tidyr) #install.packages(&amp;quot;tidyr&amp;quot;) Sample Statistics and Summary resultsMean, variance, and error values are always required for the final report. It can take a while to sort the data in the right way and several times you may want to check how your data looks frequently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Introduction</title>
      <link>/2020/09/23/stats-course-1week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/23/stats-course-1week/</guid>
      <description>Why RR is one of the most complex and sofisticated statistical softwares. Similarly, the current acceptance of the software is high in many fields and work lines. There is an infinite number of applications with R, you can have linear regressions, spatial analysis, graphs, books, journals, even APPs have been added in the last few years. Scientists are constantly updating the program and other packages for us to find it easier to interact with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started</title>
      <link>/2020/09/22/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/22/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>R studioFirst, we need to install two programs, R and R studio. You may be wondering the differences between R and R studio, we will no go in detail in this blog but, I will mention that R studio is the Graphics Interface Device that makes R much easier for us. Install the versions recommended for your machine.
Once you finished the installation open R-studio and let’s get started by installing the following packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>This site was built to provide additional information and content to the lecture slides of the course Environmental Statistics at Beijing Normal University. All the code used for the graphs is included in the posts so it can be used to replicate them with your data. Similarly, It is a page created for you to be familiar with R-Studio and other very important packages that will help you during your studies and career.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
